Zachary Bowles UX/UI Design

Portland, OR

Contact

8

zachbowles.com



znsbowles@gmail.com



626 993 7501



zacharybowles-769291163

Skills

Design

- User Flows
- WireFraming
- Prototyping
- Interaction design
- User centered design
- Information architecture
- Design strategy

Research

- User Interviews
- Competitive Research
- Comparative Analysis
- Usability Testing
- Surveys

Soft

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Time Management
- Empathy and Kindness

I offer experience in UX/UI design, small business strategy, marketing, sales, and customer support. Strategizing how to effectively utilize finite resources to maximize a small company's potential has been a large part of my young career.

Experience

2019-Present

User Success Lead at RoasterTools

- Leveraged user feature request data with subscription retention rates to concept a new business roadmap and strategy.
- Conducted a usability report of the application and composed a report of suggested solutions to improve the overall user experience of the APP.
- Created a new onboarding system and wrote help documentation to help new users learn the app faster.

2018-2019

Marketing and Sales Associate at RoasterTools

- Redesigned marketing strategy by migrating to a CRM and focussing on email outreach.
- Strategized effective outreach strategy to maximize lead engagement.
- Created a referral program as a low cost method of generating new leads
- Created a new website marketing landing page that increased web traffic by 30% through improved SEO

Zachary Bowles UX/UI Design

Portland, OR

Contact

8

zachbowles.com



znsbowles@gmail.com



626 993 7501



zacharybowles-769291163

Tools

- Sketch
- InVision
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Figma
- Abstract
- Slack
- Google Drive
- Microsoft Suite

Education

2019

Career Foundry

Certificate in UX/UI Design

- Intensive Project-based UX/UI Immersion Course
- Learned the fundamentals of UX and UI design while creating native mobile apps and responsive websites
- Focused on Human Centered Design Principles and agile methodologies

2015 -2018

Reed College, Portland OR

Bachelor of Arts, History

- Transferred to highly selective liberal arts college to pursue rigorous interdisciplinary course study; extensive research, text analysis, writing; resulted in ability to meet weekly deadlines with high level of accuracy
- Senior Thesis: Conducted year-long independent research project on Federal narcotics laws requiring highly disciplined approach to project management; read 600 pages/week, incorporated weekly feedback, organized 300 citations and multiple manuscript versions. Supervised by Professor Will Smiley (Ph.D. Yale). Resulted in 100-page publication, May, 2018.

2013 -2015

University of Arizona

 Two years of college-level courses in history, English, philosophy, and mathematics

Spring 2017

Sciences Po Lille

 Semester of courses taught in French and English